export const quizData = [
  {
    question: "An Entrepreneur is principally out there in business to _______",
    options: [
      "Make profit",
      "Deliver goods and services",
      "Pay all forms of tax",
      "Create and deliver values",
    ],
    answer: "Create and deliver values",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The word Entrepreneurship originates from the French word _______, which means 'to undertake'",
    options: ["Entreprendre", "Interprendre", "Entripendre", "Entreprendri"],
    answer: "Entreprendre",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The attributes of a good entrepreneurship include all, EXCEPT_______",
    options: [
      "Need for achievement",
      "Need to create superior value",
      "Need for innovativeness",
      "Identification of mentor",
    ],
    answer: "Identification of mentor",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In order to build long-term competitive advantage, the 21st century entrepreneurs primarily invest in _______",
    options: [
      "Plant and equipment",
      "Natural resources",
      "Shares and debentures",
      "Knowledge and social capital",
    ],
    answer: "Knowledge and social capital",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Small is beautiful is an entrepreneurship slogan propagated by the______",
    options: ["Europeans", "Germans", "Japanese", "Americans"],
    answer: "Japanese",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A globally renowned entrepreneur who made fortune through electric light bulb and phonograph is ______",
    options: ["Richard Branson", "Bill Gates", "Henry Ford", "Thomas Edison"],
    answer: "Thomas Edison",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ is a high school drop-out entrepreneur who made fortune in a small record shop in London.",
    options: ["Richard Branson", "Bill Gates", "Henry Ford", "Anita Roddick"],
    answer: "Bill Gates",
  },
  {
    question: "All are popular demographic factors EXCEPT ________",
    options: ["Self confidence", "Gender", "Education", "Family birth order"],
    answer: "Self confidence",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ is not the main responsibility in managing an entrepreneurial venture",
    options: [
      "Managing process",
      "Managing people",
      "Managing bureaucracy",
      "Managing growth and innovation",
    ],
    answer: "Managing bureaucracy",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The socio-economic values of entrepreneur include all but one ______",
    options: [
      "Employment creation",
      "Innovation",
      "Tax payment",
      "Encouraging illegal business",
    ],
    answer: "Encouraging illegal business",
  },
  {
    question:
      "For business idea to be profitable, it considers what promises/values it offers to _______",
    options: ["Employee", "Entrepreneur", "Customer", "Government"],
    answer: "Customer",
  },
  {
    question: "A good business idea must meet how many conditions _______",
    options: ["2", "3", "5", "4"],
    answer: "3",
  },
  {
    question: "An entrepreneur's next word for ‘go-between’ is _______",
    options: ["Innovator", "Futuristic", "Risk taker", "Creator"],
    answer: "Risk taker",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A business opportunity has the following qualities EXCEPT_______",
    options: [
      "The window opening lasts for a long time",
      "Is rewarding and provides significant profits and growth potential",
      "Easy feasible and achievable entry into the market",
      "Break-even takes a long time",
    ],
    answer: "Break-even takes a long time",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Business opportunity uses which of the following resources_______",
    options: [
      "Money and machine",
      "Men and material",
      "Idea",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question: "Entrepreneurs are usually referred to as_______",
    options: [
      "Intellect people",
      "Opportunists",
      "Brilliant",
      "Tribalism people",
    ],
    answer: "Opportunists",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_____ deals with the careful identification and examination of every factor of business opportunity (positive and negative effects)",
    options: [
      "Evaluation",
      "Idea generation",
      "Scanning business opportunity",
      "Market analysis",
    ],
    answer: "Scanning business opportunity",
  },
  {
    question: "Customers buy products to satisfy first their ____",
    options: ["Self", "Image", "Need", "Want"],
    answer: "Need",
  },
  {
    question: "Entrepreneur is significant in all EXCEPT_______",
    options: [
      "Income redistribution",
      "Employment potential",
      "Promote local technology",
      "Frowns at self reliance",
    ],
    answer: "Frowns at self reliance",
  },
  {
    question: "All are challenges of SMEs EXCEPT_______",
    options: [
      "Creating awareness for the product",
      "Providing benefits and value to the customers",
      "Getting acceptance by their target audience",
      "Quit break even",
    ],
    answer: "Quit break even",
  },

  // 21
  {
    question: "Marketing research process has how many key stops _______",
    options: ["3", "4", "7", "5"],
    answer: "4",
  },
  {
    question: "The first step in market research is to _______",
    options: [
      "Define the opportunity problem",
      "Design the method",
      "Develop the solution",
      "Collection of data",
    ],
    answer: "Define the opportunity problem",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The function that links the organization to its market through the gathering of analysis of information is ______",
    options: [
      "Product development",
      "Data analysis",
      "Marketing research",
      "Advertising",
    ],
    answer: "Marketing research",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Market intelligence collects data on happenings on all EXCEPT_______",
    options: [
      "Competitors offerings",
      "Ownership/Entrepreneur history",
      "Customer purchase trend",
      "Product/price changes",
    ],
    answer: "Ownership/Entrepreneur history",
  },
  {
    question: "Marketing research is a misplaced activity for SMEs_______",
    options: ["True", "False", "None of the above", "Only a and b"],
    answer: "False",
  },
  {
    question: "Which one of these is inexpensive alternative to survey myth?",
    options: [
      "Archival research",
      "Systematic observation",
      "Cross-section survey",
      "Secondary sources",
    ],
    answer: "Cross-section survey",
  },
  {
    question: "____ is not a theory of business growth in Nigeria",
    options: [
      "Franchising theory",
      "Acquisition theory",
      "Personality Theory",
      "Organic Theory",
    ],
    answer: "Personality Theory",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When one firm purchase of high strength purchase over the other, it is referred to as ________",
    options: ["Franchise", "Leasor", "Acquisition", "Merger"],
    answer: "Acquisition",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Reasons for unethical behaviours among Nigerian entrepreneurs are all EXCEPT____",
    options: [
      "Low income",
      "Poor moral background",
      "Strong code of ethic",
      "Weak sanctions",
    ],
    answer: "Strong code of ethic",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Ethical culture can be created by entrepreneur through all EXCEPT one ________",
    options: [
      "Be a visible role model",
      "Communicate ethical expectations",
      "Provide ethical training",
      "Reward mediocre",
    ],
    answer: "Reward mediocre",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_____ is the ability of the business organization to act responsibly towards its internal and external publics",
    options: [
      "Ethics",
      "Consumers",
      "Corporate social responsibility",
      "Citizenship",
    ],
    answer: "Corporate social responsibility",
  },
  {
    question: "Ethics is good in business because of all EXCEPT ________",
    options: [
      "Corporate reputation",
      "Shareholder’s trust",
      "Long term sustenance of organization",
      "Employee turnover",
    ],
    answer: "Employee turnover",
  },
  {
    question: "Family business is business that____",
    options: [
      "Owned and managed by a person",
      "Owned and run by a family member",
      "Owned and managed by family members",
      "Owned and managed by blood relation only",
    ],
    answer: "Owned and managed by family members",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An example of family business that have grown top among the list of five best in the world is ______",
    options: ["Wall Mart", "Sony", "Agofure", "Ibru"],
    answer: "Wall Mart",
  },
  {
    question: "The three circle model encompasses all EXCEPT one ________",
    options: ["Family", "Ownership", "Production", "Management"],
    answer: "Production",
  },
  {
    question: "______ is a world known entrepreneur in Microsoft business.",
    options: [
      "Chief Femi Otedola",
      "Alhaji Aliko Dangote",
      "Bill Gates",
      "Walt Disney",
    ],
    answer: "Bill Gates",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_______ was a University drop-out who eventually became a successful entrepreneur.",
    options: [
      "Chief Femi Otedola",
      "Alhaji Aliko Dangote",
      "Bill Gates",
      "Walt Disney",
    ],
    answer: "Bill Gates",
  },
  {
    question: "The entrepreneur sees business opportunities only when ______",
    options: [
      "He is creative, regularly scans the environment, and can see beyond the ordinary",
      "He has cash and connection",
      "He has God father in business",
      "He sells fake items",
    ],
    answer:
      "He is creative, regularly scans the environment, and can see beyond the ordinary",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The characteristics of a successful entrepreneur include all, EXCEPT______",
    options: [
      "Adaptability",
      "Changing the environment",
      "Innovative mindedness",
      "Analytical capability",
    ],
    answer: "Changing the environment",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which is not the difference between an entrepreneur and a manager______?",
    options: [
      "Environmental analysis",
      "Ownership status",
      "Risking bearing",
      "Reward structure",
    ],
    answer: "Environmental analysis",
  },

  // 41
  {
    question:
      "The difference between entrepreneur and other businessmen is that______",
    options: [
      "He is creative, values relationships, and delivers customer superior values",
      "He believes in transaction paradigm",
      "He takes business secret",
      "He cheats the customers",
    ],
    answer:
      "He is creative, values relationships, and delivers customer superior values",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Entrepreneur is someone who demonstrates initiatives and creative thoughts and is able to organize socio-economic mechanism to turn resources and situations practically and accepts risks and failures ______",
    options: ["True", "False", "None of the above", "All of the above"],
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question: "Opportunity recognition involves______",
    options: [
      "The ability to identify high-potential ones",
      "The ability to identify low-potential ones",
      "All of the above",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question: "The entrepreneur’s environment defines the _____",
    options: [
      "Factors and actors that influence decision-making",
      "The internal factors only that influence decision making",
      "The external factors only that influence decision-making",
      "Economic factors that influence decision-making",
    ],
    answer: "Factors and actors that influence decision-making",
  },
  {
    question:
      "All are the macro-environmental forces to be considered by an entrepreneur, EXCEPT _____",
    options: ["Technology", "Economy", "socio-politics", "Suppliers"],
    answer: "Suppliers",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the critical reason for engaging in entrepreneurship?",
    options: ["Make profit", "Play 419", "Pay tax", "Create value"],
    answer: "Create value",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The documents required of an entrepreneur to register his business in Nigeria are amongst others_____",
    options: [
      "memorandum and articles of association",
      "Address of registered office",
      "list and particulars of directors",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The entrepreneur does the following fundamental management functions _____",
    options: [
      "Planning, organizing, directing, co-ordinating, and controlling",
      "Planning, organizing, directing, fashioning and controlling",
      "Informing, organizing, directing, co-ordinating and controlling",
      "Planning, organizing, directing, co-ordinating and reporting",
    ],
    answer: "Planning, organizing, directing, co-ordinating, and controlling",
  },
  {
    question:
      "One of the options is not a critical setback to an entrepreneur _____",
    options: [
      "inability to see and tap opportunities",
      "funds",
      "Human capital",
      "Government encouragement",
    ],
    answer: "Government encouragement",
  },
  {
    question: "_____ foster entrepreneurship in mature market create",
    options: ["Opportunity", "Necessity", "Innovation", "Commitment"],
    answer: "Necessity",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The factor spurring entrepreneurship in rapid growth market create _____",
    options: ["Opportunity", "Necessity", "Innovation", "Commitment"],
    answer: "Innovation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The sources of funding entrepreneurial ideas includes but one_____",
    options: ["Equity", "Copying", "Debenture", "Personal savings"],
    answer: "Copying",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The tendency of perceive ambiguous situations as desirable is_____",
    options: [
      "Locus of control",
      "Need for achievement",
      "Risk taking propensity",
      "Tolerance for ambiguity",
    ],
    answer: "Risk taking propensity",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Major factors that influence the core process of opportunity recognition and development include the following EXCEPT ________",
    options: [
      "Entrepreneurial alertness",
      "Social networks",
      "Entrepreneurial posture",
      "Prior knowledge",
    ],
    answer: "Entrepreneurial posture",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Social entrepreneurship achieves its goals by achieving the following_____",
    options: [
      "Being passionate in the community",
      "Helping communities to define their problems",
      "Being community friendly",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Innovation represents goods, services, ideas, practices and opinions that are_____",
    options: [
      "The first in the industry",
      "One of the first in the industry",
      "The last in the industry",
      "The first or one of the first in the industry that has the capability of building for a firm a competitive advantage",
    ],
    answer:
      "The first or one of the first in the industry that has the capability of building for a firm a competitive advantage",
  },
  {
    question: "Who amongst these is a know scholar in innovation_____",
    options: [
      "Professor Ivan Pavlow",
      "Dr. B. F. Skinner",
      "Professor Everette Rogers",
      "Abraham Maslow",
    ],
    answer: "Dr. B. F. Skinner",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Early studies on entrepreneurial career choice focused on one of the following_____",
    options: [
      "Unemployment",
      "Wealth creation",
      "Inflation",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "None of the above",
  },
  {
    question:
      "One of the following is a determining factor of why people choose to become entrepreneurs _____",
    options: [
      "Attractiveness of an enterprise",
      "Availability of funds",
      "Entrepreneurship education",
      "Paying taxes to the government",
    ],
    answer: "Attractiveness of an enterprise",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_____ provides a cognitive framework that endows meaning, belief and value and explains the differences in entrepreneurial intentions",
    options: ["Geography", "Top echelon", "Culture", "GDP"],
    answer: "Culture",
  },

  // 61
  {
    question:
      "Schumpeter (1934) observes that change is a catalyst for entrepreneurial activities, thus, stable environments offer entrepreneurial opportunity_____",
    options: ["True", "False", "None of the above", "All of the above"],
    answer: "False",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Knowing the behavioural manifestations of entrepreneurship, we measure the entrepreneurial levels in the following ways EXCEPT_____",
    options: [
      "Reliably",
      "Profitably",
      "None of the above",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Profitably",
  },
  {
    question: "Which best defines an industry?",
    options: [
      "A place goods and services are manufactured",
      "A manufacturer of heavy duty machines",
      "A group of firms that compete amongst themselves",
      "A seller of goods and services",
    ],
    answer: "A group of firms that compete amongst themselves",
  },
  {
    question: "A typical example of a manufacturing industry is _____",
    options: ["Agriculture", "Mining", "Labour Market", "Automobile"],
    answer: "Automobile",
  },
  {
    question: "The father of scientific management is_____",
    options: ["Henri Fayol", "Frank Gilbert", "Elton Mayo", "F. W. Taylor"],
    answer: "F. W. Taylor",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is associated with the Hawthorne experiment and human relations management? _____",
    options: ["Henri Fayol", "Frank Gilbert", "Elton Mayo", "F. W. Taylor"],
    answer: "Elton Mayo",
  },
  {
    question: "Which is not a basis for assessing opportunities? _____",
    options: [
      "Net present value (NPV)",
      "Break-even approach",
      "Linear programming (LP)",
      "Balance sheet",
    ],
    answer: "Balance sheet",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In terms of Derr’s success measures, entrepreneurship means the following EXCEPT_____",
    options: ["Getting ahead", "Balance", "Making money", "Autonomy"],
    answer: "Making money",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_____ involves extending the firm’s domain of competence and corresponding opportunity set through internally generated new resource combinations",
    options: [
      "Firm entrepreneurship",
      "Independent entrepreneurship",
      "Organizational entrepreneurship",
      "Corporate entrepreneurship",
    ],
    answer: "Corporate entrepreneurship",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Generally entrepreneurial firms emphasize the following EXCEPT____",
    options: [
      "Technological leadership",
      "Product leadership",
      "Research & Development leadership",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question: "Risk returns trade-off emphasizes ____",
    options: [
      "The more the risk, the more the returns",
      "Risk equals returns",
      "Risk less than returns",
      "Invested cash",
    ],
    answer: "The more the risk, the more the returns",
  },
  {
    question: "The internet turns the world flat means that ____",
    options: [
      "Size and location are no more barriers to entrepreneurs",
      "Size is no more barriers to the entrepreneurs",
      "Location is no more a barrier the entrepreneurs",
      "Entrepreneurs are equal",
    ],
    answer: "Size and location are no more barriers to entrepreneurs",
  },
  {
    question: "Cash-flow statement is broken into____",
    options: [
      "cash-flow from operating activities",
      "cash-flow from investing activities",
      "All of the above",
      "Cash paid for dividend",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question: "Micro-financing provides all EXCEPT ________",
    options: [
      "Financial services to economically active sector",
      "Offers small loans",
      "Accepts small serving deposits",
      "Offers simple payment services needed by micro-entrepreneurs",
    ],
    answer: "Accepts small serving deposits",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The long-term sources of loan for entrepreneur include all EXCEPT one ____",
    options: ["Debenture", "Equity", "Preference Shares", "Bonds"],
    answer: "Bonds",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The salesman test only builds goodwill but does not take order is____",
    options: [
      "Missionary sales people",
      "Order delivery",
      "Order taker",
      "Service people",
    ],
    answer: "Missionary sales people",
  },
  {
    question: "Which one of these is not a role of sales people?",
    options: [
      "Produce product",
      "Generate sales revenue",
      "Meet buyer expectation",
      "Provide market information",
    ],
    answer: "Produce product",
  },
  {
    question: "The first step in personality selling process is ____",
    options: ["Information", "Approach", "Prospecting", "Closing sales"],
    answer: "Prospecting",
  },
  {
    question: "All these are types of sales job EXCEPT ________",
    options: [
      "Order delivery",
      "Order getting and taking",
      "Planning",
      "Missionary and creative sales people",
    ],
    answer: "Planning",
  },
  {
    question: "Canned sales is used in what stage of selling process____",
    options: ["Approach", "Presentation", "Handling objection", "Prospecting"],
    answer: "Presentation",
  },

  // 81
  {
    question:
      "The aspect of selling process that builds long lasting relationship and customer satisfaction is____",
    options: ["Closing sales", "Follow-up", "Approach", "Handling objection"],
    answer: "Follow-up",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____ is the number of stages for selling process, a sales process goes through",
    options: ["6", "7", "5", "4"],
    answer: "7",
  },
  {
    question: "____ skill is needed to handle subordinate issues and problem",
    options: [
      "Technical skill",
      "Human skill",
      "Conceptual skill",
      "Managerial skill",
    ],
    answer: "Human skill",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of this is a key knowledge required in selling____",
    options: ["Company", "Product", "Sales technique", "All of the above"],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question: "A common characteristic of a good sales person is ____",
    options: [
      "Communication ability",
      "Accommodation",
      "Empathy",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question: "The traditional P(s) of market are ____",
    options: ["2", "3", "4", "5"],
    answer: "4",
  },
  {
    question: "The extended P(s)/mix of marketing are____",
    options: ["7", "8", "6", "4"],
    answer: "7",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The various type of places where personal selling occur are EXCEPT ___________",
    options: [
      "Over the counter selling",
      "Field selling",
      "Telemarketing",
      "Shopping",
    ],
    answer: "Shopping",
  },
  {
    question: "Market coverage selling strategy is all EXCEPT one____",
    options: [
      "In intensive distribution",
      "In-narrow distribution",
      "In selective distribution",
      "In exclusive distribution",
    ],
    answer: "In-narrow distribution",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____ is all economic activities whose output/outcome is not physical or construction",
    options: ["Commodity", "Product", "Service", "Item"],
    answer: "Service",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Modern marketing tools are classified as ____ devices used for communication and drive sales",
    options: ["Electronic", "Print", "Broadcast", "Transit"],
    answer: "Electronic",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Facebook, Twitter, Blog, Website are ____ used for business activities",
    options: ["Machines", "Social media", "Communication", "Advertising"],
    answer: "Social media",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The employee who is entrusted with the responsibility to make innovation in the organization is called ____",
    options: [
      "Intrapreneur",
      "Entrepreneur",
      "Intrapersonal",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Intrapreneur",
  },
  {
    question: "An entrepreneur is ____",
    options: ["Risk-bearer", "Organizer", "Innovator", "All of the above"],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ is individuals with innovative solutions to society’s most pressing and daunting social problems",
    options: [
      "Social Entrepreneur",
      "Socialist enterprise",
      "Entrepreneur",
      "Philanthropist",
    ],
    answer: "Social Entrepreneur",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ is a good or favourable change available to run a specific business in a given environment at a given point of time",
    options: [
      "Business opportunity",
      "Optimist",
      "Savoury",
      "Business placement",
    ],
    answer: "Business opportunity",
  },
  {
    question: "____ serves as a road map in setting up a business enterprise",
    options: [
      "Business plan",
      "Business idea",
      "Business breakthrough",
      "Business",
    ],
    answer: "Business plan",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____is the attempt to create value through recognition of business opportunity, the management of risk-taking appropriate to the opportunity and through the communicative and management skills to mobilise human, financial and material resources necessary to bring a project to fruition.",
    options: [
      "Entrepreneurship",
      "Socialism",
      "Entreprepism",
      "Business model",
    ],
    answer: "Entrepreneurship",
  },
  {
    question: "The easiest form of business is ____",
    options: ["Sole proprietorship", "Partnership", "Co-operative", "Company"],
    answer: "Sole proprietorship",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The contents of a business plan include the following EXCEPT ______",
    options: ["Product", "Manpower", "Location", "Maturity"],
    answer: "Maturity",
  },

  // 101
  {
    question:
      "Entrepreneurship promotes employment opportunities in Nigeria____",
    options: ["True", "False", "Only in business", "Rivers State alone"],
    answer: "False",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Statement of cash flow contains operating, financial and investing activities of a company____",
    options: ["True", "False", "Cash book", "Income statement"],
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The following factors are impediments to entrepreneurial practice in Nigeria except____",
    options: ["The entrepreneurs’ mindset", "Fear", "Innovativeness", "Worry"],
    answer: "Innovativeness",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The various components of the external environment that directly and consistently interfere with the daily activities of the firm is known as____",
    options: ["Interest groups", "Suppliers", "Deciders", "Task environment"],
    answer: "Task environment",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The following are the common reasons why people purchase goods and services except____",
    options: ["Desirability", "Convenience", "Profitability", "Appearance"],
    answer: "Profitability",
  },
  {
    question:
      "For a new idea to be recognized as a business idea, it must be____",
    options: ["Diplomatic", "Feasible", "Viable", "d & a"],
    answer: "d & a",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A promising business idea has the following characteristics EXCEPT ________",
    options: ["Clear focus", "Profitability", "Innovativeness", "Co-operative"],
    answer: "Co-operative",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_________ is the tool employed by SMEs to identify customer needs, monitor/handle complaints and keep abreast of competitive actions.",
    options: [
      "Marketing research",
      "Market potential",
      "Sale potentials",
      "C & D",
    ],
    answer: "Marketing research",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The following methods are simple ways of collecting data by SMEs EXCEPT ________",
    options: ["Primary data", "Secondary data", "Infotech", "Observation"],
    answer: "Infotech",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A growth strategy in which a firm combines its operations at different levels of the production and marketing process is ____",
    options: [
      "Market strategy",
      "Vertical integration",
      "Penetration strategy",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Vertical integration",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_______ is defined as the art of recording business transactions in chronological and systematic manner so as to show a firm's financial position at any given date",
    options: ["Accounting", "Book keeping", "Recording", "A & B"],
    answer: "Book keeping",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The act of selecting a sub-set of the whole marketplace that a company can organize its sales efforts around or on is known as ____",
    options: ["Diversification", "Acquisition", "Segmentation", "Penetration"],
    answer: "Segmentation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "________ involves the exchange of digital information between parties such as coordination of flow of goods and services and/or transition of electronic orders/payments.",
    options: ["e-business", "e-trade", "e-commerce", "e-marketing"],
    answer: "e-commerce",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A new technology that creates a new/different approach toward performing a task in a more efficient and advantageous way that displaces existing technology is known as ____",
    options: [
      "Innovation",
      "Disruptive technology",
      "Arid strategies",
      "Run strategy.",
    ],
    answer: "Disruptive technology",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The process of adjusting a sales presentation to fit a particular selling situation is known as ____",
    options: [
      "Prospecting",
      "Consultative selling",
      "Adaptive selling",
      "Objective selling",
    ],
    answer: "Adaptive selling",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The general forms of business, ownership transfer and succession include ____",
    options: ["Liquidation", "Gifting", "Inheritance", "Integration"],
    answer: "Integration",
  },
  {
    question: "Debt and equity are major sources of ____",
    options: [
      "Entrepreneurial financing",
      "Borrowing",
      "Open market operations",
      "Business assessment",
    ],
    answer: "Entrepreneurial financing",
  },
  {
    question: "Loan financing institutions for entrepreneur are____",
    options: [
      "Commercial banks, development banks and specialist banks",
      "Merchant Bank, Development Banks and Specialist banks",
      "Money deposit banks, merchant bank and CBN",
      "Bank of the North, UBA, and FCMB",
    ],
    answer: "Money deposit banks, merchant bank and CBN",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The relationship between psychological attributes and entrepreneurial performance are generally few but____",
    options: ["Certain", "Uncertain", "Suggestive", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Suggestive",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The elementary classification between founders as entrepreneurs and successors as non-entrepreneurs avoids dependence on subjective distinctions such as the following EXCEPT____",
    options: [
      "Strategic preference",
      "Orientation towards innovation",
      "Creativity",
      "None is a factor",
    ],
    answer: "Creativity",
  },

  //121
  {
    question: "One is not an element of enlarged marketing mix____",
    options: ["Distribution", "People", "Propensity", "Positioning"],
    answer: "Distribution",
  },
  {
    question: "The basis of market segmentation includes all EXCEPT____",
    options: ["Gender", "Age group", "Income", "None of the above"],
    answer: "None of the above",
  },
  {
    question: "Fundamentally, consumer behavior covers all EXCEPT____",
    options: [
      "Searching for product",
      "Disposing of product",
      "Producing products",
      "Evaluating products",
    ],
    answer: "Producing products",
  },
  {
    question: "Balance sheet captures ____",
    options: [
      "Assets, liabilities and capital",
      "Fixed assets, current assets and equity",
      "Liabilities and capital",
      "Assets and capital",
    ],
    answer: "Assets, liabilities and capital",
  },
  {
    question: "Assets are made up of ____",
    options: [
      "Fixed and variable",
      "Land and building",
      "Cash and stock",
      "Creditor and stockholders",
    ],
    answer: "Fixed and variable",
  },
  {
    question: "Once is not an example of fixed costs____",
    options: ["Salaries", "Unskilled wages", "Land", "Building"],
    answer: "Unskilled wages",
  },
  {
    question: "Accounting books include all EXCEPT____",
    options: [
      "Balance sheet",
      "Fixed asset",
      "Cash-flow statement",
      "Statement of shareholders’ equity",
    ],
    answer: "Fixed asset",
  },
  {
    question: "The structure of income statement covers____",
    options: [
      "Revenue and cost",
      "Cost and budget",
      "Income and expenses",
      "Net income and income tax",
    ],
    answer: "Income and expenses",
  },
  {
    question:
      "All the following are techniques for analyzing financial statement EXCEPT _______",
    options: [
      "Balance sheet",
      "Ratio analysis",
      "Fund flow analysis",
      "Cash flow analysis",
    ],
    answer: "Balance sheet",
  },
  {
    question: "Break-even analysis analyzes the relationship between____",
    options: [
      "Production, operations and sales",
      "Production, operations and analysis",
      "Fixed and variable costs",
      "Sales revenue, operating costs and profits",
    ],
    answer: "Sales revenue, operating costs and profits",
  },
  {
    question: "____is not a major category of financial ratio analysis",
    options: [
      "Profitability sustainability",
      "Operational effectiveness",
      "Liquidity",
      "Autman model",
    ],
    answer: "Autman model",
  },
  {
    question: "____ is not a participant in the stock market",
    options: [
      "The Nigerian Stock Exchange",
      "Brokers",
      "Registrars",
      "Investors",
    ],
    answer: "Registrars",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ may be used for distribution of low involvement entrepreneurial products",
    options: [
      "Wholesalers → Retailers → Agents → Consumers",
      "Producers → Wholesalers → Retailers → Consumers",
      "Producers → Consumers",
      "Producers → Agents → Consumers",
    ],
    answer: "Producers → Wholesalers → Retailers → Consumers",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The informal sector provides more employment opportunities than the formal sector in the developed and emerging economies______",
    options: ["True", "False", "None of the above", "All of the above"],
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Two methods are commonly used by entrepreneurs in the 21st century to work closely with the consumers’ aspiration ____",
    options: [
      "Review of literature",
      "Forecasting",
      "Research and user interface",
      "Guessing",
    ],
    answer: "Research and user interface",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following statements is incorrect? ____",
    options: [
      "Assets – liabilities = capital",
      "Capital – liabilities = assets",
      "Assets = capital + liabilities",
      "Assets – capital = liabilities",
    ],
    answer: "Capital – liabilities = assets",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is not an asset? ____",
    options: ["Debtor", "Motor vehicle", "Creditor", "Stock of goods"],
    answer: "Creditor",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is a liability? ____",
    options: ["Cash balance", "Loan from Chinda C.", "Debtor", "Building"],
    answer: "Loan from Chinda C.",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following should not be called 'sales'? ____",
    options: [
      "Goods sold, to be paid for in one month’s time",
      "Goods sold, cash being received immediately",
      "Items previously included in purchases, now sold on credit",
      "Sale of a motor lorry not now required",
    ],
    answer: "Sale of a motor lorry not now required",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following should not be called 'purchase'? ____",
    options: [
      "Items bought for the prime purpose of resale",
      "Goods bought on credit",
      "Office stationary purchased",
      "Goods bought for cash",
    ],
    answer: "Office stationary purchased",
  },

  //141
  {
    question: "Which of these statements is incorrect? ____",
    options: [
      "profit is another word for capital",
      "A loss creases capital",
      "Profit increase capital",
      "Drawings decreases capital",
    ],
    answer: "profit is another word for capital",
  },
  {
    question: "Gross profit is____",
    options: [
      "Excess of cost of goods sold over sales",
      "Purchase + sales",
      "Net profit less expenses",
      "Excess sales over cost of goods sold",
    ],
    answer: "Excess sales over cost of goods sold",
  },
  {
    question: "Net profit is calculated on the____",
    options: [
      "Trial balance",
      "Trading account",
      "Profit and loss account",
      "Balance sheet",
    ],
    answer: "Profit and loss account",
  },
  {
    question: "The credit entry for net profit is shown in the ____",
    options: [
      "Capital account",
      "Profit and loss account",
      "Balance sheet",
      "Trading account",
    ],
    answer: "Capital account",
  },
  {
    question: "The total of the sales journal is entered on ____",
    options: [
      "The debit side of the sales day book",
      "The credit side of the sales account in the general ledger",
      "The debit side of the sales account in the general ledger",
      "The credit side of the sales daybook",
    ],
    answer: "The credit side of the sales account in the general ledger",
  },
  {
    question: "The purchase journal is best described as____",
    options: [
      "A list of purchases bought on credit",
      "Containing suppliers’ accounts",
      "A list of purchases bought for cash",
      "Part of the double entry system",
    ],
    answer: "A list of purchases bought on credit",
  },
  {
    question: "In the trading account, the returns inwards should be____",
    options: [
      "Added to cost of goods sold",
      "Deducted from purchases",
      "Deducted from sales",
      "Added to sales",
    ],
    answer: "Deducted from sales",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The descending order in which current assets should be shown in the balance are____",
    options: [
      "Debtors, bank, stock, cash",
      "Stock, debtors, bank, cash",
      "Stock, debtors, cash, bank",
      "Cash, bank, debtors, stock",
    ],
    answer: "Stock, debtors, bank, cash",
  },
  {
    question: "The purchase journal consists of____",
    options: [
      "Cash purchases",
      "Suppliers’ ledger accounts",
      "A list of purchase invoices",
      "Payment for goods",
    ],
    answer: "A list of purchase invoices",
  },
  {
    question: "A trade discount is best described as____",
    options: [
      "A discount if the invoice is paid",
      "A discount given for cash payment",
      "A discount given to suppliers",
      "A discount given to traders",
    ],
    answer: "A discount given to traders",
  },
  {
    question: "The sales journal does not contain____",
    options: [
      "Credit sales made without deduction of trade discount",
      "Credit sales made to oversee customers",
      "Cash sales",
      "Credit sales which eventually turn out to be bad debts",
    ],
    answer: "Cash sales",
  },
  {
    question: "The journal is____",
    options: [
      "Part of the double entry system",
      "A form of sales day book",
      "A form of diary",
      "A supplement to the balance sheet",
    ],
    answer: "A form of diary",
  },
  {
    question: "A petty cash book ____",
    options: [
      "Is used only in limited companies",
      "Is used when we have a bank overdraft",
      "Is used for small cheque payments",
      "will keep down the number of entries on the general ledger",
    ],
    answer: "will keep down the number of entries on the general ledger",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Any patents, trademarks, copyright or trade secrets held by the entrepreneur is known as____",
    options: [
      "Disclosure document",
      "Patent",
      "Intellectual property",
      "None of the mentioned",
    ],
    answer: "Intellectual property",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The organization will never be able to make the necessary changes without_________",
    options: [
      "Top management commitment",
      "Employees",
      "Workers",
      "None of the mentioned",
    ],
    answer: "Top management commitment",
  },
  {
    question: "The ways entrepreneurs make decisions______",
    options: [
      "Entrepreneurial domain.",
      "Reverse brain storming",
      "Heuristics",
      "Reverse brain storming",
    ],
    answer: "Entrepreneurial domain.",
  },
  {
    question: "A trademark is_______",
    options: [
      "word, symbol, name or device that a business uses to identify its goods.",
      "A legal protection for information on foreign products.",
      "Legal protection for intellectual works.",
      "Legal protection for a U.S. product exported to another country.",
    ],
    answer:
      "word, symbol, name or device that a business uses to identify its goods.",
  },
  {
    question: "Locus of control is______",
    options: ["A feeling", "Attitude", "Attribute", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Attribute",
  },
  {
    question: "Licensing arrangements have____",
    options: [
      "Low risk process involved",
      "Easy way to generate incremental income",
      "Several pitfalls",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Personal characteristics to be a successful entrepreneur includes____",
    options: [
      "Understanding environment",
      "Creating management options",
      "Encourage open discussion",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  //161
  {
    question: "International entrepreneurship is____",
    options: [
      "Licensing",
      "Exporting",
      "Both of the mentioned options",
      "None of the two mentioned",
    ],
    answer: "Both of the mentioned options",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is not a characteristic that is helpful for an entrepreneur to have?",
    options: ["Self-esteem", "Caution", "Drive", "Optimism"],
    answer: "Caution",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Hindrance for going in the international business is known as____",
    options: [
      "Synergy",
      "Turn key point",
      "Trade barrier",
      "Minority interest",
    ],
    answer: "Trade barrier",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A set of reasons for engaging in a particular behavior, especially human behavior is known as ______",
    options: ["Values", "Vision", "Entrepreneurship", "Motivation"],
    answer: "Motivation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following techniques is an excellent method for initially screening ideas and concepts in addition to generating new ideas?",
    options: [
      "Focus group",
      "Brain storming",
      "Problem inventory analysis",
      "Reverse brainstorming",
    ],
    answer: "Focus group",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The creative process for problem solving that involves making the strange familiar in first step and then making the familiar strange through personal, direct or symbolic analogy is called _________",
    options: [
      "Synectics",
      "Gordon method",
      "Checklist method",
      "Scientific method",
    ],
    answer: "Synectics",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When the multiplicity of environments become too complex to handle, the international entrepreneurs often _______",
    options: [
      "Go for mergers",
      "Diversify",
      "Decentralize operations",
      "Sale out the foreign business",
    ],
    answer: "Decentralize operations",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An entrepreneur into the hosiery business found out the reason his hosiery was not selling was due to its color. What could be the best source of this information? ____",
    options: ["Supplier", "Retailer", "Competition", "Government bureau"],
    answer: "Retailer",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In some countries, point of purchase displays is not allowed in retail stores. Such differences are studied by international entrepreneurs under __________ environment.",
    options: ["Economic", "Political", "Cultural", "Technological"],
    answer: "Cultural",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Entrepreneurial success has been significant because of the culture and the political and economic systems in _______",
    options: [
      "European countries",
      "Asian countries",
      "Transition economies",
      "Middle east",
    ],
    answer: "Asian countries",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Having more than 50% ownership position that provides the entrepreneur with managerial control is called _______",
    options: [
      "Joint venture",
      "Majority interest",
      "Horizontal merger",
      "Diversified activity merger",
    ],
    answer: "Majority interest",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The under-developed or lesser developed countries need manufacturing technology and infrastructure and yet do not want to turn over substantial portion of their economy to foreign ownership. Which of the following is a solution to this dilemma? ____",
    options: [
      "Management contract",
      "Indirect exporting",
      "Licensing",
      "Turn-key project",
    ],
    answer: "Turn-key project",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The development of a new venture based on an inventor's work often requires _______",
    options: [
      "Expertise of an entrepreneur",
      "Heavy investment from financers",
      "Skilled human resources",
      "Highly educated staff",
    ],
    answer: "Expertise of an entrepreneur",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_________ is the process in marketing of dividing a market into distinct subsets (segments) that behave in the same way or have similar needs.",
    options: [
      "Target Market",
      "Market Analysis",
      "Market Segmentation",
      "All of the Above",
    ],
    answer: "Market Segmentation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A business where an individual is both the owner and conductor of the business affairs is called___________",
    options: [
      "Sole Proprietorship",
      "Partnership",
      "Corporation",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Sole Proprietorship",
  },
  {
    question: "In ________, the entrepreneur has the right to sell any assets.",
    options: [
      "Proprietorship",
      "Partnership",
      "Limited Liability Company",
      "None of the given options",
    ],
    answer: "Proprietorship",
  },
  {
    question:
      "__________are lists of the general tasks, or functions, and responsibilities of a position.",
    options: [
      "Job Specifications",
      "Job descriptions",
      "Job Requirements",
      "Jobholder",
    ],
    answer: "Job descriptions",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A__________ can be a budget, a plan for spending and saving future income.",
    options: [
      "Marketing Plan",
      "Financial Plan",
      "Production Plan",
      "Organizational Plan",
    ],
    answer: "Financial Plan",
  },
  {
    question:
      "__________ involves an interest-bearing instrument, usually a loan, the payment of which is only indirectly related to sales and profits.",
    options: [
      "Equity Financing",
      "Internal or External Funds",
      "Banking Funds",
      "Debt Financing",
    ],
    answer: "Debt Financing",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The idea and actions that explain how a firm will make its profits refers to____",
    options: ["Mission", "Goal", "Strategy", "Objective"],
    answer: "Strategy",
  },
  //181
  {
    question: "SBIR stands for____",
    options: [
      "Small Business Information Research",
      "Small Business Innovation Research",
      "Small Business Intelligent Research",
      "Small Business Inventory Research",
    ],
    answer: "Small Business Innovation Research",
  },
  {
    question: "_______is what the 'W' in the SWOT analysis stands for.",
    options: ["Wedge", "Work/life", "Worth of Business", "Weakness"],
    answer: "Weakness",
  },
  {
    question: "Benefits can focus on which of these?",
    options: [
      "Value and Cost",
      "Imitation and Innovation",
      "Internal and External aspects",
      "None of the given options",
    ],
    answer: "Value and Cost",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An entrepreneur's primary motivation for starting a business is_______",
    options: [
      "To make money",
      "To be independent",
      "To be famous",
      "To be powerful",
    ],
    answer: "To be independent",
  },
  {
    question: "To be successful in an entrepreneurial venture, you need____",
    options: ["Money", "Luck", "Hard work", "A good idea"],
    answer: "Luck",
  },
  {
    question: "Entrepreneurs are best as______",
    options: ["Managers", "Venture capitalists", "Planners", "Doers"],
    answer: "Doers",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A successful entrepreneur relies on which of the following for critical management advice______",
    options: [
      "Internal management team",
      "External management professionals",
      "Financial sources",
      "No one",
    ],
    answer: "External management professionals",
  },
  {
    question: "Entrepreneurs typically form______",
    options: [
      "Service businesses",
      "Manufacturing companies",
      "Constructive companies",
      "A variety of ventures",
    ],
    answer: "A variety of ventures",
  },
  {
    question: "Entrepreneurs______",
    options: [
      "Are the life of the party",
      "Are bores at a cocktail party?",
      "Will never go to parties",
      "Just fit into the crowd at a party",
    ],
    answer: "Just fit into the crowd at a party",
  },
  {
    question: "Entrepreneurs and venture capitalists:",
    options: [
      "Get along well",
      "Are the best friends",
      "Are cordial friends",
      "Are in conflict",
    ],
    answer: "Are in conflict",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An entrepreneur's primary motivation for high ego and need for achievement is based upon a relationship with______",
    options: ["Spouse", "Mother", "Father", "Children"],
    answer: "Father",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An individual usually begins his or her first significant entrepreneurial business enterprise at what age______",
    options: ["Teens", "Twenties", "Forties", "Fifties"],
    answer: "Forties",
  },
  {
    question: "NAFTA is acronym for______",
    options: [
      "North American Free Trade Agreements",
      "North Asian Free Trade Agreements",
      "National Asian Free Trade Agreements",
      "National American Free Trade Agreements",
    ],
    answer: "North American Free Trade Agreements",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The factor______ is probably the most prevalent reason for mergers.",
    options: ["Taxation", "Economies of scale", "Inflation", "Mergers"],
    answer: "Economies of scale",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A ______ merger is a combination of two firms producing the same products but selling them in different geographic markets.",
    options: [
      "Diversified Activity Merger",
      "Product Extension Merger",
      "Vertical Merger",
      "Market Extension Merger",
    ],
    answer: "Market Extension Merger",
  },
  {
    question:
      "One of the most frequent reasons an entrepreneur forms a joint venture is to share the______",
    options: ["Resources", "Cost", "Cost and risk of a project", "Profit"],
    answer: "Cost and risk of a project",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_______ involves having a foreign purchaser in the local market or using an export management firm.",
    options: [
      "Direct Exporting",
      "Indirect Exporting",
      "Management Contracts",
      "Turn-Key Projects",
    ],
    answer: "Indirect Exporting",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The _______measures the payments that flow between any individual country and all other countries.",
    options: [
      "International Business",
      "Economies of Scales",
      "Balance of Payment",
      "None of the given options",
    ],
    answer: "Balance of Payment",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_________ is an entrepreneurial type who quickly identifies new promising business opportunities but rarely, if ever, follows through on the opportunity to create a successful new venture.",
    options: [
      "Simplicity Sue",
      "Shotgun Sam",
      "Hidden Agenda Harry",
      "Inventor Irving",
    ],
    answer: "Shotgun Sam",
  },
  {
    question:
      "One study found that the typical minority business owner was the______",
    options: [
      "Oldest child in a blue-collar family and married.",
      "Oldest child in a white-collar family and married.",
      "Youngest child in a blue-collar family and married.",
      "Youngest child in a white-collar family and married.",
    ],
    answer: "Oldest child in a blue-collar family and married.",
  },
  //201
  {
    question: "Traditional managers are____",
    options: [
      "Deals with mistakes and failures",
      "Tries to avoid mistakes and surprises",
      "Attempts to hide risky projects from view until ready",
      "None of the given Options",
    ],
    answer: "Tries to avoid mistakes and surprises",
  },
  {
    question: "Entrepreneurs are____",
    options: [
      "Moderate risk taker",
      "High risk taker",
      "Avoidance",
      "Both b and c",
    ],
    answer: "Moderate risk taker",
  },
  {
    question: "Risk decisions are often postponed until____",
    options: [
      "Hard facts can be gathered or a consultant hired to illuminate the unknown.",
      "Hard facts can be gathered or an auditor hired to illuminate the unknown.",
      "There is no need to gather facts and hired a consultant/auditor",
      "None of the given options",
    ],
    answer:
      "Hard facts can be gathered or a consultant hired to illuminate the unknown.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____ is one method of stimulating, and then capitalizing on, individuals in an organization who think that something can be done differently and better.",
    options: [
      "Strategic Orientation",
      "Capitalization",
      "Intrapreneurship",
      "Management",
    ],
    answer: "Intrapreneurship",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The typical ______ has a climate and reward system that favor conservative decision making.",
    options: [
      "Entrepreneurship culture",
      "Corporate culture",
      "Intrapreneurial culture",
      "None of the given options",
    ],
    answer: "Corporate culture",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Female entrepreneurs normally start their venture at the age of ______ years.",
    options: ["35-45", "25-30", "20-25", "40-45"],
    answer: "35-45",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Male entrepreneurs normally start their venture at the age of_____ years.",
    options: ["20-25", "25-35", "40-50", "After the age of retirement."],
    answer: "25-35",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The _______ is the process through which innovation develops and commercializes through entrepreneurial activity, which in turn stimulates economic growth.",
    options: [
      "Product-evolution process",
      "Technological innovations",
      "Breakthrough innovations",
      "None of the given options",
    ],
    answer: "Product-evolution process",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A__________ is a type of company formed from research and development that usually does not go public.",
    options: [
      "Foundation",
      "Life-Style Firm",
      "High-Potential Venture",
      "Both b and c",
    ],
    answer: "Foundation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_______involve such things as writing, listening, oral presentations, coaching and technical know-how.",
    options: [
      "Business Management skills",
      "Personal entrepreneurial skills",
      "Technical skills",
      "None of the given options",
    ],
    answer: "Technical skills",
  },
  {
    question: "The _______ means to do things in his or her own way and time.",
    options: [
      "Need per independence",
      "Need for achievement",
      "Personal values",
      "Ethics",
    ],
    answer: "Need per independence",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ is a reason or set of reasons for engaging in a particular behavior, especially human behavior.",
    options: ["Moral value", "Act", "Motivation", "None of the options"],
    answer: "Motivation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The _______ plan shows whether the business is economically feasible or not.",
    options: ["Financial", "Business", "Economic", "Marketing"],
    answer: "Business",
  },
  {
    question: "The term entrepreneur is translated as ______",
    options: ["between-giver", "between-taker", "receiver", "giver"],
    answer: "between-taker",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The period in which the money person entered into a contract with the go-between to sell his goods is known as ______",
    options: ["middle area", "18th century", "17th century", "Earliest period"],
    answer: "Earliest period",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ viewed the entrepreneur as a risk taker who 'buy(s) at an uncertain price, therefore operating at a risk'",
    options: [
      "Eli Whitney",
      "Edward Harriman",
      "Richard cantilena",
      "Thomas Edison",
    ],
    answer: "Richard cantilena",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A ______ is a professional money manager who makes risk investment from a pool of equity capital to obtain a high rate of return on investments",
    options: ["venture capitalist", "entrepreneur", "businessman", "Buyer"],
    answer: "venture capitalist",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In the ______ century, the notion of an entrepreneur as an innovator was established.",
    options: [
      "17th century",
      "Late 19th century",
      "middle of the 20th century",
      "18th century",
    ],
    answer: "middle of the 20th century",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In almost all definitions of entrepreneurship there is agreement that we are talking about a kind of behavior that includes______",
    options: [
      "initiative taking",
      "the organizing and reorganizing or social/economic mechanisms to turn resources and situations to practical account.",
      "the acceptance of risk or failure",
      "all of the given option",
    ],
    answer: "all of the given option",
  },
  {
    question: "One effective way to begin the marketing plan is______",
    options: [
      "To make a list of the information that will be needed to prepare the marketing plan.",
      "Gathering Data from Secondary Sources",
      "Gathering Information from Primary Sources.",
      "None of the options given",
    ],
    answer:
      "To make a list of the information that will be needed to prepare the marketing plan.",
  },
  {
    question: "A focus group______",
    options: [
      "Is a sample of 10 or 12 potential investors who participate in a discussion?",
      "Is a sample of 10 or 12 potential employees who participate in a discussion?",
      "Is a sample of 10 or 12 potential customers who participate in a discussion?",
      "None of the options given",
    ],
    answer:
      "Is a sample of 10 or 12 potential customers who participate in a discussion?",
  },
  {
    question: "The situation analysis is______",
    options: [
      "Defining Target Market/Opportunities and Threats.",
      "Considering Strengths and Weaknesses",
      "A review of where the company has been and considers environmental factors.",
      "None of the options given",
    ],
    answer:
      "A review of where the company has been and considers environmental factors.",
  },
  {
    question: "One of the difficult decisions______",
    options: [
      "Is about the distribution of the product",
      "Is determining the appropriate price for the product.",
      "Is about the promotion of the product",
      "None of the options given",
    ],
    answer: "Is determining the appropriate price for the product.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following statement is true for marketing system? ______",
    options: [
      "It is all about the internal envoi mental factors",
      "It identifies the major interacting components, both internal and external",
      "It's about the financial needs of the venture",
      "None of the options given",
    ],
    answer:
      "It identifies the major interacting components, both internal and external",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In setting marketing goals and objectives the entrepreneur must______",
    options: [
      "Set the price",
      "Distribution place",
      "Must satisfy customers",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "None of the above",
  },
  {
    question: "The financial plan provides a complete picture of______",
    options: [
      "How much and when the funds are coming into the organization.",
      "Where the funds are going.",
      "How much cash is available?",
      "All of the options given",
    ],
    answer: "All of the options given",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Before developing the pro forma income statement, the entrepreneur should______",
    options: [
      "Prepare operating budgets",
      "Capital budgets.",
      "None of the options given",
      "Both of the options given (a,b)",
    ],
    answer: "Both of the options given (a,b)",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following statement is true?",
    options: [
      "Cash flow is same as profit.",
      "Profit is the result of subtracting expenses from sales.",
      "Cash flow results from the difference between all cash available and cash payments.",
      "Cash flows only when actual payments are not made but only received.",
    ],
    answer: "Profit is the result of subtracting expenses from sales.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Personal characteristics to be a successful entrepreneur includes______",
    options: [
      "Understanding environment",
      "Creating management options",
      "Encourage open discussion",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question: "Without top management commitment, the organization will______",
    options: [
      "Be able to make changes",
      "Not be able to make any changes",
      "Not be able to make effective changes",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Not be able to make any changes",
  },
  {
    question: "Locus of control is______",
    options: ["A feeling", "Attitude", "Attribute", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Attribute",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Entrepreneurial experience becomes increasingly important as______",
    options: [
      "Work load increases",
      "Complexity of venture increases",
      "Complexity of work increases",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Complexity of venture increases",
  },
  {
    question: "Entrepreneurs are concerned about basic issues of______",
    options: [
      "Sales, costs and benefits",
      "Customers, sales and costs",
      "Risk, costs and benefits",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Sales, costs and benefits",
  },
  {
    question: "Licensing arrangements have______",
    options: [
      "Low risk process involved",
      "Easy way to generate incremental income",
      "Several pitfalls",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question: "Joint ventures have been used by entrepreneur______",
    options: [
      "When the entrepreneur wants to purchase local knowledge",
      "When rapid entry into the market is needed",
      "Both of the options given",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Both of the options given",
  },
  {
    question:
      "First stage of production planning and development processes is______",
    options: [
      "Idea stage",
      "Concept stage",
      "Establishing and evaluating criteria stage",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Establishing and evaluating criteria stage",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The importance of intellectual property should be understood by entrepreneur even before_______",
    options: [
      "Hiring a manager",
      "Engaging an attorney",
      "Developing a product",
      "Establishing new venture",
    ],
    answer: "Engaging an attorney",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is not followed in brainstorming?",
    options: [
      "Criticism is done by the group members",
      "The wilder idea is better",
      "Quantity of ideas is required",
      "The session should be fun, with no one dominating the discussion",
    ],
    answer: "Criticism is done by the group members",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The former USSR received technology and syrup from Pepsi and provided it with Soviet vodka and rights to distribute it in the US. This is an example of______",
    options: [
      "Economic development",
      "Barter system",
      "Balance of payment",
      "International trade",
    ],
    answer: "Barter system",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A patent is granted for a specified amount of time because of the assumption______",
    options: [
      "During this time firm will cover its development costs",
      "Firm will earn a sufficient profit during this period",
      "To limit the monopoly of the firm",
      "It will stimulate idea and development of a better product",
    ],
    answer: "It will stimulate idea and development of a better product",
  },

  //241
  {
    question:
      "Developing a new idea through inquiry and testing is called ______",
    options: [
      "Heuristics",
      "Scientific method",
      "Forced relationship",
      "Value analysis",
    ],
    answer: "Scientific method",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In an international perspective, which of the following decisions are not covered under strategic planning of an entrepreneur? ______",
    options: [
      "What are unique characteristics of each market?",
      "Who should be involved in marketing decisions?",
      "What customer benefits are provided by the product",
      "What are the company's major strengths and weaknesses?",
    ],
    answer: "What are unique characteristics of each market?",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following grants the owner protection from anyone else making, using and selling the identified innovation? ______",
    options: [
      "Utility patent",
      "Design patent",
      "Plant patent",
      "International patent",
    ],
    answer: "Utility patent",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The problem inventory analysis should be used primarily to______",
    options: [
      "Reflect a new business opportunity",
      "Identify product idea for further evaluation",
      "Solve unknown problems",
      "Develop a list of problems",
    ],
    answer: "Identify product idea for further evaluation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Selling goods to another country through a person in the entrepreneur's home country is known as ______",
    options: ["Export", "Direct export", "Indirect export", "Domestic sales"],
    answer: "Indirect export",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following statements is not true about trademarks? ______",
    options: [
      "A trademark could be a slogan or a particular sound",
      "Some trademarks have no relationship with the product",
      "The filing date for the trademark becomes the first date use of the mark",
      "The entrepreneur cannot file after the mark already been in use",
    ],
    answer: "The entrepreneur cannot file after the mark already been in use",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The product life cycle is included in which stage of product planning and development process? ______",
    options: [
      "Test marketing stage",
      "Product development stage",
      "Commercialization stage",
      "Product planning and development process is a part of product life cycle",
    ],
    answer: "Commercialization stage",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following cannot be covered under the copyright protection? ______",
    options: [
      "Computer software",
      "Computer hardware",
      "Poems and songs",
      "Models and sculpture",
    ],
    answer: "Computer hardware",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Idea of new product is tested in potential consumers to determine consumer acceptance at the_________ stage.",
    options: [
      "Concept",
      "Product development",
      "Test marketing",
      "Commercialization",
    ],
    answer: "Concept",
  },
  {
    question:
      "According to the governing bodies of common laws, the life of trade secret is______",
    options: [
      "12 years",
      "17 years",
      "20 years",
      "As long as it remains confidential",
    ],
    answer: "As long as it remains confidential",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is used by entrepreneurs to acquire experience in an International market before making a major commitment? ______",
    options: [
      "Merger",
      "Joint venture",
      "Minority interest",
      "Majority interest",
    ],
    answer: "Minority interest",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The evaluation criteria for the new product should include all of the following except______",
    options: [
      "Determination of market demand",
      "Determination of the suppliers",
      "Pricing and marketing policies of other competing firms",
      "Product should be profitable",
    ],
    answer: "Determination of the suppliers",
  },
  {
    question: "Licensing is a significant marketing strategy to______",
    options: [
      "Use intellectual property of others",
      "Pirate others' patents",
      "Grow the business in new markets",
      "Control the costs",
    ],
    answer: "Grow the business in new markets",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Automated stock replenishment, electronic selling and processing of customers orders and payments are examples of________",
    options: ["E-business", "E-commerce", "E-trading", "E-transaction"],
    answer: "E-business",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The longest lasting trade agreement with the objective of liberalizing trade by eliminating or reducing tariffs, subsidies and quotas is ______",
    options: [
      "Free trade area (FTA)",
      "European community (EC)",
      "General agreement on tariffs and trade (GATT)",
      "The North American free trade agreement (NAFTA)",
    ],
    answer: "General agreement on tariffs and trade (GATT)",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The most important characteristic of a successful business website is_____",
    options: ["Speed", "Innovation", "Graphics", "Products"],
    answer: "Speed",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Many companies are attempting to create the same ______ of entrepreneurship in the organization.",
    options: ["Spirit", "Culture", "Reward", "All"],
    answer: "All",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The typical _____ has a climate and reward system that favors conservative decision making.",
    options: [
      "Entrepreneurial process",
      "Opportunity identification",
      "Entrepreneurial culture",
      "Corporate culture",
    ],
    answer: "Corporate culture",
  },
  {
    question:
      "There is/are individual characteristic(s) needed for a person to be successful entrepreneurs, _____",
    options: [
      "Understanding the environment",
      "Been visionary and flexible",
      "Creating management options",
      "All",
    ],
    answer: "All",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Without _____ commitment, the organization will never be able to make the necessary changes.",
    options: ["Top management", "Upper management", "Middle management", "All"],
    answer: "Top management",
  },
  {
    question:
      "With _____ cut backs, more control has been given to lower levels of the organization.",
    options: [
      "Top management",
      "Upper management",
      "Middle management",
      "Lower management",
    ],
    answer: "Middle management",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Women are now starting new ventures at _____ time(s) the rate of men.",
    options: ["One", "Two", "Three", "Four"],
    answer: "Three",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A/an _____ an individual who creates something for the first time, is a highly driven individual motivated by his or her own work and personal ideas.",
    options: ["Entrepreneur", "Inventor", "Salesman", "Investor"],
    answer: "Inventor",
  },
  {
    question: "An entrepreneur falls in love with the new _____",
    options: ["Industry", "Invention", "Venture", "None"],
    answer: "Venture",
  },
  {
    question: "What causes people to do something ______",
    options: [
      "Motivations",
      "Need for achievement",
      "Need for independence",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Motivations",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_____ is the process of an entrepreneur conducting business activities across national boundaries.",
    options: [
      "National entrepreneurship",
      "International entrepreneurship",
      "Both a and b",
      "None of the given option",
    ],
    answer: "International entrepreneurship",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An entrepreneur is concerned about the same basic issue(s) _____",
    options: ["Sales", "Costs", "Profits", "All"],
    answer: "All",
  },
  {
    question: "A countries’ _____ affects the valuation of its currency.",
    options: [
      "Economics",
      "Culture and traditions",
      "Balance of payments",
      "Technological environment",
    ],
    answer: "Balance of payments",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Laws governing business arrangements also vary in the _____ different legal systems and sets of national laws.",
    options: ["150", "50", "100", "95"],
    answer: "150",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To understand what is required for effective planning, reporting and control the entrepreneur should consider________",
    options: [
      "Environment analysis",
      "Strategic planning",
      "Operating planning",
      "All",
    ],
    answer: "All",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Lesser-developed countries are able to obtain manufacturing technology without surrendering economic control through _____",
    options: [
      "Licensing",
      "Turn key projects",
      "Direct foreign investment",
      "Direct exporting",
    ],
    answer: "Turn key projects",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A _____ Is the combination of two firms that produce closely related projects in the same area?",
    options: [
      "Product extension merger",
      "Vertical merger",
      "Horizontal merger",
      "Diversified activity merger",
    ],
    answer: "Horizontal merger",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_____ is a creative process that forces individuals to solve problems through one of four analysis mechanisms, personal, direct, symbolic and fantasy.",
    options: ["Ordain method", "Checklist method", "Brainstorming", "Synaptic"],
    answer: "Synaptic",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_____ method is a method of developing new ideas when the individuals are unaware of the problem.",
    options: [
      "Synaptic",
      "Ordain method",
      "Reverse brainstorming",
      "Matrix charting",
    ],
    answer: "Ordain method",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Following is/are the factor(s) that facilitate the growth of e-commerce are________",
    options: [
      "The widespread use of personal computers",
      "The adoption of intranets in companies",
      "The acceptance of the internet as a business communications platform",
      "All",
    ],
    answer: "All",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The product life cycle is generally divided into the following stage(s)________",
    options: [
      "Product introduction",
      "Market growth and maturity",
      "Sales decline",
      "All",
    ],
    answer: "All",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The entrepreneur should first file a _____ to establish a date of conception",
    options: [
      "The patent application",
      "The disclosure document",
      "Patent infringement",
      "None",
    ],
    answer: "The disclosure document",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A _____ must have become distinctive and aimed recognition before it can be registered.",
    options: [
      "Arbitrary mark",
      "Selective mark",
      "Descriptive mark",
      "Trade mark",
    ],
    answer: "Descriptive mark",
  },
  {
    question: "A _____ protects original works of authorship.",
    options: ["Trade marks", "Trade secrets", "Copyrights", "All"],
    answer: "Copyrights",
  },
  {
    question: "The consumer product safety Act, passed in_____",
    options: ["1986", "1972", "1970", "1965"],
    answer: "1972",
  },
  {
    question: "Common types of insurance include________",
    options: [
      "Property insurance",
      "Casualty and life insurance",
      "Bonding",
      "All",
    ],
    answer: "All",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Insurance companies calculate the premium for workers' compensation as a percentage of________",
    options: ["Payrolls", "Type of business", "Prior claim", "All"],
    answer: "All",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The perspective(s) need to be considered in the business plan is/are________",
    options: ["Entrepreneur", "Investor", "Marketing perspective", "All"],
    answer: "All",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The _____ provides a brief summary of the business plan's contents.",
    options: [
      "Executive summary",
      "Introductory page",
      "Environmental and industry analysis",
      "Description of the venture",
    ],
    answer: "Introductory page",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The creative process for problem solving that involves making the strange familiar in first step and then making the familiar strange through personal, direct or symbolic analogy is called________",
    options: [
      "Synectics",
      "Ordain method",
      "Checklist method",
      "Scientific method",
    ],
    answer: "Synectics",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is included in the description of the business? _____",
    options: ["Location", "Products offered", "History", "All"],
    answer: "All",
  },
  {
    question: "Why should an entrepreneur do a feasibility study? _____",
    options: [
      "To see if there are possible barriers to success",
      "To identify possible sources of funds",
      "To estimate the expected sales",
      "To explore potential customers",
    ],
    answer: "To see if there are possible barriers to success",
  },
  {
    question: "Brand in business represents the following EXCEPT_____",
    options: ["Name", "Term", "Symbol", "All of the above"],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question: "Branding is pervasive of which management process_____",
    options: ["Planning", "All the stages/process", "Organizing", "Strategy"],
    answer: "All the stages/process",
  },
  {
    question: "Brand represents picture that governs ____ mind",
    options: ["Government", "Consumer", "Employee", "Student"],
    answer: "Consumer",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Branding is the process of activities of giving a particular product a ____",
    options: ["Value", "Choice", "Name", "Management"],
    answer: "Name",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The aspect of brand that can be verbalized and vocalized is ____",
    options: ["Brand Symbol", "Brand Name", "Brand Colour", "Brand Design"],
    answer: "Brand Name",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The aspect of brand that require legal protection and registration is____",
    options: ["Trade Mark", "Trade Name", "Brand Colour", "Brand Name"],
    answer: "Trade Name",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Fulani herdsmen practice branding of putting marks/sign at the back of ____",
    options: ["Mans", "Buildings", "Cows", "Trees"],
    answer: "Cows",
  },
  {
    question: "Which one of these is not a role of brand? _____",
    options: [
      "Source of maker",
      "Reduce risk of choice making",
      "Inventory/tracking record",
      "Depletion",
    ],
    answer: "Depletion",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The role of brand that allows entrepreneur to reap from the creatively investment is _____",
    options: [
      "Asset",
      "Intellectual property right",
      "Inventory right",
      "Goodwill right",
    ],
    answer: "Intellectual property right",
  },

  //301
  {
    question:
      "_____ quality of brand allows for easy recognition and recall by consumer",
    options: ["Memorable", "Meaningful", "Adaptable", "Protectable"],
    answer: "Memorable",
  },
  {
    question: "Which one of these is not a quality of brand _____",
    options: ["Adjustable", "Protectable", "Memorable", "Meaningful"],
    answer: "Adjustable",
  },
  {
    question: "CANIRIV is an example of which type of brand_____",
    options: ["Idea", "Person", "Product", "Event"],
    answer: "Event",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Using your own district, unique and innovative name for different version of product is called_____",
    options: [
      "Individual brand name",
      "Family brand name",
      "Generic branding",
      "Corporate brand name",
    ],
    answer: "Individual brand name",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Using an organization name for all the products of that firm is ____",
    options: [
      "Corporate name",
      "Individual name",
      "Generic name",
      "Co-branding name",
    ],
    answer: "Corporate name",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Shell/NNPC joint venture is an example of what branding approach_____",
    options: [
      "Family name",
      "Co-branding name",
      "Individual name",
      "Company name",
    ],
    answer: "Co-branding name",
  },
  {
    question: "_____ is the value endowed in a brand",
    options: ["Brand management", "Brand equity", "Brand joy", "Brand asset"],
    answer: "Brand equity",
  },
  {
    question: "The first process of strategic brand equity starts with ____",
    options: [
      "Consumer brand research",
      "Brand element",
      "Integrated marketing",
      "Continuous innovation",
    ],
    answer: "Consumer brand research",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The aspect of brand building that considers every internal unit/department is important is_______",
    options: [
      "Integrated marketing",
      "Competitor research",
      "Brand element",
      "Secondary association",
    ],
    answer: "Integrated marketing",
  },
  {
    question: "The publics of an entrepreneur are all EXCEPT one _____",
    options: ["Banks", "Government", "Host communities", "The company itself"],
    answer: "The company itself",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ is the process of exchanging idea, goods and services for an amount of money or for anything of value",
    options: ["Selling", "Trade by barter", "Personal", "Transaction"],
    answer: "Selling",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The art of selling or persuading customer to buy represents ____",
    options: ["Personal selling", "Trade", "Salesmanship", "Mass media"],
    answer: "Salesmanship",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_________ refers to one’s belief in one’s ability to succeed in specific situations and/or accomplish task",
    options: ["Self-efficacy", "Determination", "Ability", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Self-efficacy",
  },
  {
    question: "The uncontrollable environment is also called_____",
    options: ["Internal", "Controllable", "Task", "Political"],
    answer: "Task",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The environment that makes it difficult to recognize raw opportunities is found in ___",
    options: ["Plan", "Structure", "Task", "Internal"],
    answer: "Task",
  },
  {
    question:
      "___ and ____ are the two major components of entrepreneur environment",
    options: ["The market", "Non-market", "a and b", "None of the above"],
    answer: "a and b",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Social, political and legal arrangements are under ____ environment",
    options: ["Market", "Internal", "Non market", "Economic"],
    answer: "Non market",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The sum total of forces/factors outside the entrepreneur and the firm that hinder business development is ____",
    options: ["Political", "Environment", "Risk", "Culture"],
    answer: "Environment",
  },
  {
    question: "The government role is summed into _____",
    options: ["Regulatory", "Supportive", "a and b", "None of the above"],
    answer: "a and b",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which one of these is not an incentive used by government to encourage entrepreneurs_____",
    options: [
      "Tax holiday",
      "Exportation",
      "Inflation",
      "Infrastructure development",
    ],
    answer: "Inflation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____ defines the existence of unmet and unsatisfied need which can be profitably tapped",
    options: ["Business", "Business idea", "Business opportunity", "Market"],
    answer: "Business opportunity",
  },
  {
    question: "Entrepreneurship business start first with_____",
    options: [
      "Production",
      "Accounting/record keeping",
      "Market need identification",
      "Human Resource",
    ],
    answer: "Market need identification",
  },
  {
    question: "The first essence of entrepreneurship is to _____",
    options: ["Create need", "Make money", "Satisfy need", "Develop business"],
    answer: "Satisfy need",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Customers are more concerned with what benefit they get than product _____",
    options: ["Time", "Place", "Feature", "Price"],
    answer: "Feature",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Entrepreneurship is driven by poverty, newer and better ways of accomplishing familiar tasks are summed as ___",
    options: [
      "Creativity/Innovation",
      "Development",
      "Technology",
      "Best practices",
    ],
    answer: "Creativity/Innovation",
  },
  {
    question: "A concept that can be used to make money is ____",
    options: ["Concept", "Business idea", "Market need", "Brain storming"],
    answer: "Concept",
  },
  {
    question: "Entrepreneurship entails_____",
    options: [
      "Converting idea to market product/service and for money",
      "Converting weakness to strength",
      "Conceptual new idea only",
      "a and c",
    ],
    answer: "Converting idea to market product/service and for money",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The following are the characteristics of a good business idea EXCEPT_____",
    options: ["Innovative", "Unique", "Imitation", "Original"],
    answer: "Imitation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In which of the following, the ownership of venture is reflected by ownership of shares of stock? _____",
    options: [
      "Partnership",
      "Limited partnership",
      "Corporation",
      "Proprietorship",
    ],
    answer: "Corporation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Bankers say that most businesses fail because of the _____ inability to plan properly.",
    options: ["Investor's", "Marketer's", "Entrepreneur's", "Consultant's"],
    answer: "Entrepreneur's",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The _______ of a venture could be that the company has experience in related business.",
    options: ["Strength", "Weakness", "Opportunity", "Threat"],
    answer: "Strength",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The marketing plan should focus on strategies and for the first year, goals and strategies should be projected _______",
    options: ["Daily", "Weekly", "Monthly", "Quarterly"],
    answer: "Monthly",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is not a characteristic of marketing plan? _____",
    options: [
      "It should provide a strategy to accomplish the company mission",
      "It should provide for the use of existing resources",
      "It should be simple and short",
      "It should be rigid",
    ],
    answer: "It should be rigid",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Secondary data can be obtained from all of the following sources, except________",
    options: ["Internet", "Magazine", "Bureau of statistics", "Focus group"],
    answer: "Focus group",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is one of the simplest form and lowest in entry costs_____",
    options: [
      "Direct mail marketing",
      "Online marketing",
      "Sales promotion",
      "Export marketing",
    ],
    answer: "Direct mail marketing",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In ________, the death of entrepreneur results in the termination of venture.",
    options: [
      "Proprietorship",
      "Limited company",
      "Limited partnership",
      "Corporation",
    ],
    answer: "Proprietorship",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In partnership, the ability to raise capital depends on the __________ of the business.",
    options: ["Expansion", "Success", "Size", "Nature"],
    answer: "Success",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is NOT recognized as an important component to organizational vision? _____",
    options: [
      "The vision should be built on a foundation of the organization's core values and beliefs.",
      "The vision should elaborate a purpose for the organization.",
      "The vision should include a brief summary of what the organization does.",
      "The vision should specify detailed and short-term goals.",
    ],
    answer: "The vision should specify detailed and short-term goals.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following components of organizational vision and mission statements tells how the organizational unit is responsive to societal, community, and environmental issues? _____",
    options: ["Customer", "Market", "Self-Concept", "Concern for public image"],
    answer: "Concern for public image",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following dimensions of organizational culture describes the degree to which employees are expected to do their jobs with precision, thorough analysis, and attention to detail? _____",
    options: [
      "Innovation and risk-taking",
      "Team orientation",
      "Aggressiveness",
      "Attention to detail",
    ],
    answer: "Attention to detail",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following does NOT represent a method through which organizational culture is learned? _____",
    options: ["Stories", "Conflict", "Rituals", "Material symbols"],
    answer: "Conflict",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is NOT recognized as an important purpose of a business plan? _____",
    options: [
      "Development tool for organizational founders",
      "Vision and mission clarification",
      "Planning and evaluation guidelines",
      "All of the selections are recognized as important purposes of a business plan.",
    ],
    answer:
      "All of the selections are recognized as important purposes of a business plan.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is NOT recognized as a major area that should be included in a business plan? _____",
    options: [
      "Executive summary",
      "Corporate culture differences",
      "Analysis of the opportunity",
      "Analysis of the context",
    ],
    answer: "Corporate culture differences",
  },
  {
    question:
      "All of the following are important elements of the financial data and projections section of a business plan EXCEPT_____",
    options: [
      "SWOT analysis",
      "Projected income statements",
      "Break-even analysis",
      "Cost controls",
    ],
    answer: "SWOT analysis",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A (n) ______ is a form of organization in which the owner maintains complete control over the business and is personally liable for business debts.",
    options: [
      "Sole proprietorship",
      "General partnership",
      "Corporation",
      "Limited liability Company",
    ],
    answer: "Sole proprietorship",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A (n) _____ is a form of business organization in which two or more business owners share the management and risk of the business",
    options: [
      "Limited liability Company",
      "General partnership",
      "Corporation",
      "Sole proprietorship",
    ],
    answer: "General partnership",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A (n) ______ is a form of business organization in which there are general partners and limited liability partners.",
    options: [
      "Sole proprietorship",
      "General partnership",
      "Limited liability partnership",
      "Corporation",
    ],
    answer: "Limited liability partnership",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A (n) ______ is a legal business entity that is separate from its owners and managers.",
    options: [
      "Sole proprietorship",
      "General partnership",
      "Corporation",
      "Limited liability Company",
    ],
    answer: "Corporation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A (n) ______ is a form of legal protection for a distinctive word, name, phrase, logo, symbol, design, slogan, or any combination of these elements.",
    options: ["Trademark", "Patent", "Contract", "Procedure"],
    answer: "Trademark",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is NOT one of the three different types of patents? _____",
    options: [
      "Utility patent",
      "Design patent",
      "Plant patent",
      "All the selections are valid type of patent.",
    ],
    answer: "All the selections are valid type of patent.",
  },

  //351
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is recognized as the most common type of patent? _____",
    options: [
      "Utility patent",
      "Design patent",
      "Plant patent",
      "Cultural patent",
    ],
    answer: "Utility patent",
  },
  {
    question:
      "All of the following are signals of potential decline in organizational performance EXCEPT________",
    options: [
      "Poor communication within the organization",
      "Intolerance of work incompetence",
      "Fear of conflict and taking risks",
      "Negative cash flow",
    ],
    answer: "Intolerance of work incompetence",
  },
  {
    question:
      "All of the following are recognized as important people practices of successful organizations EXCEPT________",
    options: [
      "Employment security",
      "Selective hiring",
      "Increased status differences",
      "Training",
    ],
    answer: "Increased status differences",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of an effective team? _____",
    options: [
      "External support",
      "Clear goals",
      "Irrelevant skills",
      "Mutual trust",
    ],
    answer: "Irrelevant skills",
  },
  {
    question: "In brainstorming_____",
    options: [
      "No criticism is allowed",
      "Quantity of ideas is desired",
      "None of the mentioned options",
      "Both of the mentioned options",
    ],
    answer: "Both of the mentioned options",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A technique that asks questions about objects or ideas in an effort to develop a new idea is_____",
    options: [
      "Heuristics",
      "Matrix charting",
      "Forced relationships",
      "Attribute listing",
    ],
    answer: "Forced relationships",
  },
  {
    question: "The solution development is_____",
    options: [
      "Big-Dream approach",
      "Parameter Analysis",
      "Creative synthesis",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Creative synthesis",
  },
  {
    question: "Perceived benefits /risks involve the following factors________",
    options: [
      "Utility to customer",
      "Consumption habits",
      "Buying motives",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    question: "A patent is_____",
    options: [
      "A document between government and an inventor",
      "Grants holder protection from others making, using, or selling similar idea",
      "A public domain",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer:
      "Grants holder protection from others making, using, or selling similar idea",
  },
  {
    question: "Marketing mix includes________",
    options: ["Product or service", "Financing", "Consumer", "Retailer"],
    answer: "Product or service",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following statement is true for tax advantage of proprietorship? _____",
    options: [
      "There is double tax on profits",
      "There is no capital stock tax or penalty for retained earnings",
      "Both of the options given",
      "None of the options given",
    ],
    answer: "There is no capital stock tax or penalty for retained earnings",
  },
  {
    question: "Industry analysis should include information on________",
    options: [
      "Market size of competitor's product",
      "Growth rate of suppliers",
      "New products entry",
      "Economic conditions",
    ],
    answer: "Economic conditions",
  },
  {
    question: "We need to update the business plan because _____",
    options: [
      "Environmental factors and internal factors can change the direction of the plan",
      "Goals set by the entrepreneurs may be unreasonable.",
      "Goals may not be measurable.",
      "Goals may not be specific",
    ],
    answer:
      "Environmental factors and internal factors can change the direction of the plan",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Marketing research involves the gathering of data in order to determine information as________",
    options: [
      "Who will buy the product?",
      "What price should be charged?",
      "What is the most effective promotion strategy?",
      "All of the mentioned options",
    ],
    answer: "All of the mentioned options",
  },
  {
    question: "The most often used type of funds is_____",
    options: [
      "Internally generated funds",
      "Externally generated funds",
      "Commercial bank funds",
      "None of the mentioned options",
    ],
    answer: "Internally generated funds",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is not a type of Bank Loans? _____",
    options: [
      "Inventory loans",
      "Accounts payable loans",
      "Equipment loans",
      "Real estate loans",
    ],
    answer: "Accounts payable loans",
  },
  {
    question: "Conventional bank loans include________",
    options: [
      "Lines of credit",
      "Installment loans",
      "Straight commercial loans",
      "All of the mentioned options",
    ],
    answer: "All of the mentioned options",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When an entrepreneur is unable to secure a regular commercial bank loan, an alternative is a________",
    options: [
      "Small and medium enterprise loan",
      "Character loan",
      "Small Business Administration (SBA) Guaranty Loan",
      "Equipment loan",
    ],
    answer: "Small Business Administration (SBA) Guaranty Loan",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Installment loans can be obtained by a going venture with a track record of________",
    options: [
      "Sales and profits",
      "Customers",
      "Supplier's chain",
      "All of the mentioned options",
    ],
    answer: "Sales and profits",
  },
  {
    question: "What causes people to do something? _____",
    options: [
      "Need for achievement",
      "Need for independence",
      "Motivation",
      "None of the mentioned options",
    ],
    answer: "Motivation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Individuals who help the entrepreneur in business activities_____",
    options: [
      "Role models",
      "Professional-support network",
      "Parents",
      "None of the mentioned options",
    ],
    answer: "Professional-support network",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The managers in an organization strongly supporting intrapreneurship is called _____",
    options: [
      "Top management commitment",
      "Upper management commitment",
      "Lower management intrapreneur",
      "Upper management intrapreneur",
    ],
    answer: "Top management commitment",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_____ involves a manufacturer giving a foreign manufacturer the right to use a patent, trademark or technology in return for a royalty",
    options: [
      "Licensing",
      "Turn-key projects",
      "Management contracts",
      "None of the mentioned options",
    ],
    answer: "Licensing",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In chronological age, most entrepreneurs start their careers between ages_____",
    options: [
      "22 and 55",
      "30 and 55",
      "40 and 65",
      "None of the given options",
    ],
    answer: "22 and 55",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_______ is the combination of at least two firms doing similar businesses at the same market level.",
    options: [
      "Diversified activity Merger",
      "Horizontal Merger",
      "Joint Venture",
      "Vertical Merger",
    ],
    answer: "Horizontal Merger",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is NOT recognized as a misconception about entrepreneurship? _____",
    options: [
      "Entrepreneurship is found only in small businesses.",
      "Entrepreneurship is easy.",
      "Successful entrepreneurship needs only a great idea.",
      "Entrepreneurial ventures and small businesses are different",
    ],
    answer: "Entrepreneurial ventures and small businesses are different",
  },
  {
    question:
      "All of the following are recognized as potential sources of entrepreneurial ideas EXCEPT________",
    options: [
      "Work experiences, skills, and abilities",
      "Familiar and unfamiliar products and services",
      "Personal interests or hobbies",
      "All of the selections are recognized as potential sources of entrepreneurial ideas.",
    ],
    answer:
      "All of the selections are recognized as potential sources of entrepreneurial ideas.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An __________ is an individual who creates something for the first time, is a highly driven individual motivated by his or her own work and personal ideas.",
    options: [
      "Entrepreneur",
      "Inventor",
      "Both a and b",
      "None of the given options",
    ],
    answer: "Inventor",
  },
];
